João Santos

Full-Stack Developer

Personal Info



+39 34 55 29 89 55



j-almeidasantos@hotmail.com



j-almeidasantos



jsantos42



j-almeidasantos.tech



Bari, IT

Languages

Portuguese	C
≒ English	C
French	Bź
Italian	B
Spanish	B [.]

Tech Stack









express **NEXT**_{Js}



















With a background in Medicine and 6+ years of clinical practice, I grew tired of working with poorly-designed and non-intuitive software. Healthcare software needs a dramatic uplift, and I decided to be part of that change.

The turning point came when working on the thesis of my Masters in Clinical Nutrition: I did a datascience project involving geospatial data analysis with Python and R. I liked it so much that I enrolled at 42 to become a programmer and ended up dropping my residence with only 1y left to finish.

Passionate and curious by nature, I love to learn and be challenged. At haelsi, I am lucky enough to have both, and I get to build software for my fellow colleagues!

Experience

Oct 2022 - present

Full Stack Developer (remote)

haelsi (Vienna)

- Leveraging my background as a doctor to develop a user-centric EMR software
- Collaborating with a cross-functional team in a full remote work environment
- Maintaining and enhancing an existing web application, using Ember.js on the frontend and Laravel (PHP) on the backend
- **Containerising** the existent web application to create a staging environment
- Conducting comprehensive testing (QUnit and PHPUnit) and debugging
- Utilising Python for creating scripts and automation tools and streamlining manual tasks
- Conducting thorough code reviews, debugging, and bug fixing
- Working in an agile environment, including daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospectives, to ensure timely project delivery
- Collaborating with stakeholders and end users, to gather feedback and implement new features

Jan 2022 - Jun 2022

Software Engineer Intern

Critical Techworks (Lisbon)

- Working on the frontend of BMW's cars' infotainment, developing the Human Machine Interface (HMI) of the Navigation panel
- Maintaining the existing codebase (in C++)
- Adding new features and making Unit Tests
- Adding new UI with the QT framework

Jun 2020

- Dec 2021

Graduate Student Researcher

Universidade de Lisboa

- The thesis of my Master degree in Clinical Nutrition involved:
- Geospatial data analysis using Python and R - Making use of Jupiter notebook and geopandas

Oct 2014

- Jul 2021

Medical Doctor

ARSLVT (Lisbon), APHP (Paris)

- Medical student and resident "externe" in Paris (Oct 2014 Jul 2016)
- Clerkship in Uppsala (Jul 2015)
- GP resident in Lisbon + working shifts in the ER department of the largest hospital in the country (Mar 2018 - Jul 2021)

Education

Oct 2020

Software Engineering Course

- Oct 2022

42 Lisboa

Sep 2018

Master's Degree in Clinical Nutrition

- Dec 2021

Universidade de Lisboa

Sep 2010 - Jul 2016

Doctor of Medicine

Universidade de Lisboa & Pierre et Marie Curie Université

Hobbies

Cycling Hiking Cooking Reading Learning Traveling Sailing